AII FFN TRAN

aileen.tran27@gmail.com | 714.235.8906 | <u>www.linkedin.com/in/aileentran27</u> | <u>github.com/aileentran</u>

ABOUT

I was previously a health psychology researcher at UCSF and UC Berkeley and a Doctor of Physical Therapy candidate at UCSF until I created a dynamic debt calculator. It felt so empowering to make a tool that I needed that it catalyzed my interest in engineering and I've never looked back!

My other passions include yoga, traditional tea ceremonies, martial arts (black belt in Tae Kwon Do), and snuggling all animals in sight.

PROJECTS

alwaysroamin.com github.com/aileentran/roam | All roads lead to Rome. Roam

A full-stack Flask web application for commuters that allows for accurate commute time predictions. Features include: adding multiple stops, customizing each stop's mode of transportation, map visuals, directions text.

- Users can register and login safely due to password hashing via werkzeug.security
- Compare travel time of all saved routes by passing stop addresses and mode of transportation to Distance Matrix API
- Parsed JSON string returned from Distance Matrix API to convert live traffic time values to days, hours, and
- After choosing a route, there are 2 AJAX calls: (1) information passed to Maps API to draw complete path on map and generate directions text, (2) generate customized markers with labels at stops in numerical order Stack: PostgreSQL, Python, Flask, SQLAlchemy, Javascript, AJAX, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Google Maps API, AWS Lightsail

WORK EXPERIENCE

Auamedix San Francisco, CA

Documentation Specialist

January 2016 – January 2017

- Formulated medical notes in the Electronic Health Record (EHR) for doctors, which increased productivity by 15% and increased clinician satisfaction by 40%
- Trained new scribes on several doctors' preferences and specialty to guarantee information accuracy

Barbara Laraia, Ph.D., MPH, RD

University of California, Berkeley

Public Health Nutrition Department | Research Assistant

October 2015 – January 2016

- Assisted in home visits which includes recording body measurements and guiding mother through survey, behavioral tasks, food diary, and stress diary for the ongoing, longitudinal National Health and Growth Study
- Designed easy-to-use package of body measurement tools, diaries, and records for long-distance participants

Elissa Epel, Ph.D.

University of California, San Francisco

Aging, Metabolism, and Emotions Lab | Staff Research Associate

July 2015 – October 2015

- Facilitated clinic visits including asking health questions, taking vitals and body measurements, and preparing the survey for the baseline measurements of the Healthy Beverage Initiative Study published on Oct 28, 2019
- Coordinated communication between the on-site clinic team, supervisor, nursing staff, and blood lab for seamless clinic visits of 214 participants
- Trained all research associates by leading them through the several clinic visits and shadowing their clinic visits

EDUCATION

Hackbright Academy

San Francisco, CA

Software Engineering Fellowship – Accelerated, 12 week program for women

September 2019 – December 2019

University of California, Los Angeles

Psychology, B.A. GPA: 3.69

Los Angeles, CA

September 2013 – June 2015